<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../Schema/IC-Docbook/DocbookIC.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="../../Schematron/ISM/ISM_XML.sch" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<d:article xmlns:d="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
           xmlns:ism="urn:us:gov:ic:ism"
           ism:DESVersion="202111.202211"
           ism:ISMCATCESVersion="202211"
           ism:resourceElement="true"
           ism:createDate="2017-10-18"
           ism:compliesWith="USGov USIC"
           ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA"
           version="5.0-variant urn:us:gov:ic:docbook-201804">
  <info xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA">Rogers' Rangers</title>
    <date>2017-07-03</date>
    <author>
      <orgname>My Intel Agency</orgname>
    </author>
    <mediaobject>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/MIA_Logo.png"
                   align="center"
                   width="3in" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
    <releaseinfo role="usa.nsi.banner">UNCLASSIFIED</releaseinfo>
    <legalnotice ism:unregisteredNoticeType="DISTRO">
      <title ism:classification="U"
             ism:ownerProducer="USA">Distribution Notice</title>
      <para ism:classification="U"
            ism:ownerProducer="USA">This information is for example purposes. The text contained within this report is derived from 
      <link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
            xlink:href="http://rogersrangers.org" />and is subject to the distribution restrictions, if any, imposed by the authors of the
            website.</para>
    </legalnotice>
    <abstract>
      <title ism:classification="U"
             ism:ownerProducer="USA">Executive Summary</title>
      <para ism:classification="U"
            ism:ownerProducer="USA">From 1754 to 1763 Europe and the Americas were caught up in a conflict between England, under King
            George II, and France, under King Louis XV. In Europe this period was known as the Seven Years' War; in North America it came
            to be called the French and Indian War. It was a conflict over trade and land.</para>
    </abstract>
  </info>
  <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        ism:classification="U"
        ism:ownerProducer="USA">The English sent Crown forces from England to fortify the colonies and fight the French and Indian
        invaders, but it was also necessary to recruit soldiers from the colonial population. The English army found that fighting an enemy
        in the near-wilderness of North America was too much for their massed regiments. The dense forests and mountainous terrain required
        fighting men who knew the habits of the enemy and could serve effectively as scouts and skirmishers.</para>
  <blockquote xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <para ism:classification="U"
          ism:ownerProducer="USA">"…I do therefore Hereby Constitute and Appoint you the said Robert Rogers to be Captain of an Independent
          Company of Rangers to be forthwith raised and Employ'd…" 
    <citation>Major Rogers' Diary</citation></para>
  </blockquote>
  <figure xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA">Major Robert Rogers</title>
    <mediaobject>
      <alt>Major Rogers</alt>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/rogers.gif"
                   align="center" />
      </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        ism:classification="U"
        ism:ownerProducer="USA">Men from local communities and nearby states were recruited to join ranger companies in the Hudson Valley
        campaign. The New Hampshireman Robert Rogers formed the most notable of these ranger companies.</para>
  <blockquote xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <para ism:classification="U"
          ism:ownerProducer="USA">"On the 23d, I waited on the General, and met with a very friendly reception; he soon intimated his
          design of giving me the command of an independent company of rangers, and the very next morning I received the commission, with a
          set of instructions."</para>
  </blockquote>
  <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        ism:classification="U"
        ism:ownerProducer="USA">Rogers grew up in southern New Hampshire, in an area which had known years of murderous Indian raids. He
        had the knowledge and the spirit to make a good ranger commander, and both he and his brother James joined the war in the King's
        service as rangers. Soon his own company, Rogers' Rangers, was in service in the upper Hudson River area where they became known
        for their successful but unorthodox tactics.</para>
  <table xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA">Personnel Authorization</title>
    <tgroup cols="4">
      <colspec colnum="1"
               colname="004"
               colwidth="1*" />
      <colspec colnum="2"
               colname="005"
               colwidth="1*" />
      <colspec colnum="3"
               colname="002"
               colwidth="1*" />
      <colspec colnum="4"
               colname="003"
               colwidth="1*" />
      <thead>
        <row>
          <entry>Captains</entry>
          <entry>Ensigns</entry>
          <entry>Sergeants</entry>
          <entry>Privates</entry>
        </row>
      </thead>
      <tbody>
        <row>
          <entry>1</entry>
          <entry>1</entry>
          <entry>3</entry>
          <entry>60</entry>
        </row>
        <row>
          <entry>10 Shillings per day</entry>
          <entry>5 Shillings per day</entry>
          <entry>4 Shillings per day</entry>
          <entry>3 Shillings per day</entry>
        </row>
      </tbody>
    </tgroup>
  </table>
  <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        ism:classification="U"
        ism:ownerProducer="USA">The Rangers wore distinctive green outfits and practiced tactics called "Rogers' Rules of Ranging," which
        the British considered unconventional. Rogers hired men solely on merit and shocked regular commanders with his use of Indians and
        freed slaves.</para>
  <para xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
        ism:classification="U"
        ism:ownerProducer="USA">
    <emphasis role="bold">Rogers’ Rules of Ranging:</emphasis>
    <orderedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">All Rangers are to be subject to the rules and articles of war; to appear at roll- call every
              evening, on their own parade, equipped, each with a Firelock, sixty rounds of powder and ball, and a hatchet, at which time
              an officer from each company is to inspect the same, to see they are in order, so as to be ready on any emergency to march at
              a minute's warning; and before they are dismissed, the necessary guards are to be draughted, and scouts for the next day
              appointed.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">Whenever you are ordered out to the enemies forts or frontiers for discoveries, if your number be
              small, march in a single file, keeping at such a distance from each other as to prevent one shot from killing two men,
              sending one man, or more, forward, and the like on each side, at the distance of twenty yards from the main body, if the
              ground you march over will admit of it, to give the signal to the officer of the approach of an enemy, and of their number,
              &amp;c.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you march over marshes or soft ground, change your position, and march abreast of each other to
              prevent the enemy from tracking you (as they would do if you marched in a single file) till you get over such ground, and
              then resume your former order, and march till it is quite dark before you encamp, which do, if possible, on a piece of ground
              which that may afford your centries the advantage of seeing or hearing the enemy some considerable distance, keeping one half
              of your whole party awake alternately through the night.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">Some time before you come to the place you would reconnoitre, make a stand, and send one or two men
              in whom you can confide, to look out the best ground for making your observations.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you have the good fortune to take any prisoners, keep them separate, till they are examined, and
              in your return take a different route from that in which you went out, that you may the better discover any party in your
              rear, and have an opportunity, if their strength be superior to yours, to alter your course, or disperse, as circumstances
              may require.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you march in a large body of three or four hundred, with a design to attack the enemy, divide your
              party into three columns, each headed by a proper officer, and let those columns march in single files, the columns to the
              right and left keeping at twenty yards distance or more from that of the center, if the ground will admit, and let proper
              guards be kept in the front and rear, and suitable flanking parties at a due distance as before directed, with orders to halt
              on all eminences, to take a view of the surrounding ground, to prevent your being ambuscaded, and to notify the approach or
              retreat of the enemy, that proper dispositions may be made for attacking, defending, &amp;c. And if the enemy approach in
              your front on level ground, form a front of your three columns or main body with the advanced guard, keeping out your
              flanking parties, as if you were marching under the command of trusty officers, to prevent the enemy from pressing hard on
              either of your wings, or surrounding you, which is the usual method of the savages, if their number will admit of it, and be
              careful likewise to support and strengthen your rear-guard.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you are obliged to receive the enemy's fire, fall, or squat down, till it is over; then rise and
              discharge at them. If their main body is equal to yours, extend yourselves occasionally; but if superior, be careful to
              support and strengthen your flanking parties, to make them equal to theirs, that if possible you may repulse them to their
              main body, in which case push upon them with the greatest resolution with equal force in each flank and in the center,
              observing to keep at a due distance from each other, and advance from tree to tree, with one half of the party before the
              other ten or twelve yards. If the enemy push upon you, let your front fire and fall down, and then let your rear advance
              thro' them and do the like, by which time those who before were in front will be ready to discharge again, and repeat the
              same alternately, as occasion shall require; by this means you will keep up such a constant fire, that the enemy will not be
              able easily to break your order, or gain your ground.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you oblige the enemy to retreat, be careful, in your pursuit of them, to keep out your flanking
              parties, and prevent them from gaining eminences, or rising grounds, in which case they would perhaps be able to rally and
              repulse you in their turn.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you are obliged to retreat, let the front of your whole party fire and fall back, till the rear
              hath done the same, making for the best ground you can; by this means you will oblige the enemy to pursue you, if they do it
              at all, in the face of a constant fire.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If the enemy is so superior that you are in danger of being surrounded by them, let the whole body
              disperse, and every one take a different road to the place of rendezvous appointed for that evening, which must every morning
              be altered and fixed for the evening ensuing, in order to bring the whole party, or as many of them as possible, together,
              after any separation that may happen in the day; but if you should happen to be actually surrounded, form yourselves into a
              square, or if in the woods, a circle is best, and, if possible, make a stand till the darkness of the night favours your
              escape.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If your rear is attacked, the main body and flankers must face about to the right or left, as
              occasion shall require, and form themselves to oppose the enemy, as before directed; and the same method must be observed, if
              attacked in either of your flanks, by which means you will always make a rear of one of your flank-guards.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you determine to rally after a retreat, in order to make a fresh stand against the enemy, by all
              means endeavour to do it on the most rising ground you come at, which will give you greatly the advantage in point of
              situation, and enable you to repulse superior numbers.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">In general, when pushed upon by the enemy, reserve your fire till they approach very near, which will
              then put them into the greatest surprize and consternation, and give you an opportunity of rushing upon them with your
              hatchets and cutlasses to the better advantage.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">When you encamp at night, fix your centries in such a manner as not to be relieved from the main body
              till morning, profound secrecy and silence being often of the last importance in these cases. Each centry therefore should
              consist of six men, two of whom must be constantly alert, and when relieved by their fellows, it should be done without
              noise; and in case those on duty see or hear any thing, which alarms them, they are not to speak, but one of them is silently
              to retreat, and acquaint the commanding officer thereof, that proper dispositions may be made; and all occasional centries
              should be fixed in like manner.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">At the first dawn of day, awake your whole detachment; that being the time when the savages the
              savages chuse to fall upon their enemies, you should by all means be in readiness to receive them.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If the enemy should be discovered by your detachments in the morning, and their numbers are superior
              to yours, and a victory doubtful, you should not attack them till the evening, as then they will not know your numbers, and
              if you are repulsed, your retreat will be favoured by the darkness of the night.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">Before you leave your encampment, send out small parties to scout round it, to see if there be any
              appearance or track of an enemy that might have been near you during the night.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">When you stop for refreshment, chuse some spring or rivulet if you can, and dispose your party so as
              not to be surprised, posting proper guards and centries at a due distance, and let a small party waylay the path you came in,
              lest the enemy should be pursuing.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If, in your return, you have to cross rivers, avoid the usual fords as much as possible, lest the
              enemy should have discovered, and be there expecting you.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you have to pass by lakes, keep at some distance from the edge of the water, lest, in case of an
              ambuscade or an attack from the enemy, when in that situation, your retreat should be cut off.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If the enemy pursue your rear, take a circle till you come to your own tracks, and there form an
              ambush to receive them, and give them the first fire.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">When you return from a scout, and come near our forts, avoid the usual roads, and avenues thereto,
              lest the enemy should have headed you, and lay in ambush to receive you, when almost exhausted with fatigues.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">When you pursue any party that has been near our forts or encampments, follow not directly in their
              tracks, lest they should be discovered by their rear guards, who, at such a time, would be most alert; but endeavour, by a
              different route, to head and meet them in some narrow pass, or lay in ambush to receive them when and where they least expect
              it.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you are to embark in canoes, battoes, or otherwise, by water, chuse the evening for the time of
              your embarkation, as you will then have the whole night before you, to pass undiscovered by any parties of the enemy, on
              hills, or other places, which command a prospect of the lake or river you are upon.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">In padling or rowing, give orders that the boat or canoe next the sternmost, wait for her, and the
              third for the second, and the fourth for the third, and so on, to prevent separation, and that you may be ready to assist
              each other on any emergency.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">Appoint one man in each boat to look out for fires, on the adjacent shores, from the numbers and size
              of which you may form some judgment of the number that kindled them, and whether you are able to attack them or not.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you find the enemy encamped near the banks of a river or lake, which you imagine they will attempt
              to cross for their security upon being attacked, leave a detachment of your party on the opposite shore to receive them,
              while, with the remainder, you surprize them, having them between you and the lake or river.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para ism:classification="U"
              ism:ownerProducer="USA">If you cannot satisfy yourself as to the enemy's number and strength, from their fire, &amp;c.
              conceal your boats at some distance, and ascertain their number by a reconnoitering party, when they embark, or march, in the
              morning, marking the course they steer, &amp;c. when you may pursue, ambush, and attack them, or let them pass, as prudence
              shall direct you. In general, however, that you may not be discovered by the enemy upon the lakes and rivers at a great
              distance, it is safest to lay by, with your boats and party concealed all day, without noise or shew; and to pursue your
              intended route by night; and whether you go by land or water, give out parole and countersigns, in order to know one another
              in the dark, and likewise appoint a station every man to repair to, in case of any accident that may separate you."</para>
      </listitem>
    </orderedlist>
  </para>
  <note xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA">Attachments</title>
    <para ism:classification="U"
          ism:ownerProducer="USA">A sample uniform of one of the Rangers is being shipped by the courier AntiqueMovers in a special van to
          preserve the uniform. The shipment id is AM-45897. The shippers contact number is (123) 345-7890.</para>
  </note>
  <simplesect xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
    <title ism:classification="U"
           ism:ownerProducer="USA">Bibliography</title>
    <bibliolist>
      <biblioentry>
        <abbrev>Major Rogers' Diary</abbrev>
        <title ism:classification="U"
               ism:ownerProducer="USA">Major Rogers' Diary</title>
        <author>
          <personname>Major Robert Rogers</personname>
        </author>
      </biblioentry>
    </bibliolist>
  </simplesect>
</d:article>
